MIKE ACORD

SENIOR SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

acordmike@gmail.com 1-920-224-4584 http://www.mikeacord.com

Seasoned application developer and solutions consultant with over 14 years of experience in designing, developing, and implementing database and web applications using Microsoft technologies. Specialties include C#, ASP.Net MVC, SQL Server development and administration and SharePoint deployment, development and administration.

SKILLS

WEB JAVASCRIPT HTML 5 CSS LAMP MVC REST CSS

JAVASCRIPT ANGULAR.JS JQUERY BACKBONE.JS

DATABASE SQL SERVER TSQL INTEGRATION SERVICES ANALYSIS SERVICES REPORTING SERVICES

CLOUD AZURE

PROJECT AGILE TFS

DEVOPS TFS TEAM CITY OCTOPUS DEPLOY

SHAREPOINT ADMINISTRATION DEVELOPMENT OFFICE 365

EMPLOYMENT

Senior Solutions Architect, Consultant, Omni Resources

2012-07 — Present

Senior Microsoft Architect, building solutions for clients

- Led team creating web-based report designer and high-performance report execution engine for a student management system
- Worked on team developing a dealer showcase website in Azure using ASP.Net MVC, web services and Backbone.JS
- Developed new data warehouse for an insurance company using SQL Server, AWS and Redshift.
- Developed a flexible interview building and reporting application for a health outcome reporting company
- Internal systems management and administration

Agile C# DevOps Javascript ASP.Net MVC SQL Server Analysis Services Integration Services SharePoint Azure Business Intelligence Office365 TFS Administration

SharePoint/Business Intelligence Technical Lead / Consultant,

2008-06 - 2012-07

Heartland Business Systems (Avastone)

Designing and developing custom .Net, Business Intelligence and SharePoint solutions for businesses. Management technical consulting team.

- School District teacher evaluation system developed in SharePoint, .Net and javascript
- County health reporting and analytics system developed in ASP.Net MVC
- School District website rewrite developed in SharePoint
- New product workflow application developed in InfoPath
- Data Warehouse developed on SQL Server database and Analysis Services
- Numerous SharePoint implementations, upgrades and custom development projects

C# Javascript ASP.Net MVC SQL Server Analysis Services Integration Services Sharepoint Business Intelligence

Business Intelligence Consultant, Fujitsu Consulting

2006-08 - 2008-04

Senior BI Consultant building data integration solutions. Designing and developing data migration strategy from legacy system

SSIS SQL Server ASP.Net C# Reporting Services

Business Intelligence Consultant, Compuware

SQL Server development and optimization

2005-05 - 2006-07

- Performed IT administration and deployments for Dunder Mifflin.
 - MS Access development
 - Crystal Reports development

SQL Server MS Access Crystal Reports

Systems Analyst, DRS Power & DRS Power & Control Technologies

2001-08 - 2005-08

Internal application development and support

- Gather and analyze business requirements
- Use application development methodologies to create internal business applications
- Lead cross-functional, multi-site teams to facilitate and improve business processes using technology
- Provide managers with business intelligence from raw data

SQL Server DTS ASP VB.Net

EDUCATION

MS in Management-Electronic Business, University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee

2002-08 - 2003-12

1998-08 - 2002-05Business and Computer Systems, International Business, Milwaukee School of Engineering